accenturefederal.com 2017-11-29

# Accenture Privacy Statement

## GENERAL

This page tells you everything you need to know about How Accenture protects your personal data and what your rights are in relation to your personal data:

You will also find further information on this page about:

Your Website Data  
Your Cookie Data (and other tracking technologies)  
Your Marketing Data  
Your Online Recruitment Data

If you have any questions concerning data privacy or you want to let us know about website/marketing permissions, please see how to Contact Us below.

Any changes we may make in the future to “How Accenture protects your personal data” or the statements you see here will be posted on this page. 

This privacy statement is effective August 10, 2016

**How Accenture protects your personal data**  
Accenture protects your personal data through its "Binding Corporate Rules" or "BCR." These consist of:

  * **Data Privacy Policy 90** – a global data privacy policy that sets out the safeguards that apply across Accenture regardless of where we process your data

  * **Data Privacy Procedures** – such as how we should handle access requests or complaints and 

  * **Intercompany Agreement** – an agreement to make Accenture’s Data Privacy Policy 90 and Data Privacy Procedures binding on all the participating Accenture group entities

Together, these ensure that appropriate data privacy safeguards are in place across our organization. Our BCR reflect the standards contained in European data privacy laws and have been approved by data privacy regulators in Europe (the European Economic Area and Switzerland).

Having BCR means that all our group entities that sign up to our BCR have to comply with the same internal rules. It also means that your rights stay the same no matter where your data are processed by Accenture (see Your Rights below).

[Download a full copy of Accenture’s BCR](https://www.accenture.com/t20170802T012846Z__w__/us-en/_acnmedia/PDF-52/Accenture-Public-Facing-BCR-June-2017.pdf#zoom=50 "Click here to download the full article. Description of Accenture’s Binding Corporate Rules. This opens a new window.").

**Accenture’s Data Privacy Policy 90**  
The following section summaries Accenture’s Data Privacy Policy 90. If you would like a full copy of the policy please Contact Us.

What personal data do we collect?  
Will we share your personal data with outside parties?  
What about sensitive personal data?  
What about data security?  
Where will your personal data be processed?  
Retention of your data  
Your rights  
Questions and Complaints

**What personal data do we collect?**  
We collect personal data of our workers, candidates, suppliers, business contacts, shareholders and website users. We will always try to give individuals appropriate notice of what data will be collected and how it will be used. Whatever happens, we will only process that data if we consider it fair and lawful to do so. 

**Will we share your personal data with outside parties?**  
We may transfer personal data to our contracted service providers and advisors who may be located in other countries. Before we do so, we take steps to ensure that your personal data will be given adequate protection as required by relevant data protection laws and Accenture’s internal policies.

However, there will be other times when we need to share or disclose personal data you provide for a specific purpose, for example:

  * In the case we are running a joint event and have informed you that the data will be shared with our partners. But again, we will notify you as to why we are asking for specific information and it is completely up to you whether you want to provide it;

  * We may need to disclose your personal data to third parties in the event that we sell or liquidate any part of our business or assets;

  * We will disclose or share your personal data to comply with any legal obligation, or to enforce or apply our Terms of Use; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Accenture, our clients, or others.

**What about sensitive personal data?**  
We do not generally seek to collect sensitive personal data (also known as special categories) through this site or otherwise. In the limited cases where we do seek to collect such data, we will do this in accordance with local data privacy law requirements. If you choose to provide us with unsolicited sensitive personal data, you consent to our using the data, subject to applicable law as described in this privacy policy. The term "sensitive personal data" refers t the various categories of personal data identified by European and other data privacy laws as requiring special treatment, including in some circumstances the need to obtain explicit consent. These categories may include personal identity numbers, financial account information, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious, philosophical or other similar beliefs, membership of a trade union or profession or trade association, physical or mental health, biometric or genetic data, sexual life, or criminal record (including information about suspected criminal activities).

**What about data security?**  
We take appropriate steps to maintain the security of personal data collected. Regarding your use of our websites you should understand that the open nature of the Internet is such that information and personal data may flow over networks connecting you to our systems without security measures and may be accessed and used by people other than those for whom the data is intended. 

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the sites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these sites, please note that these sites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies or sites. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these sites.

**Where will your personal data be processed?**  
As a global organization with global IT systems, personal data we collect may be routed, stored, or transferred internationally throughout Accenture's worldwide organization in accordance with our Binding Corporate Rules and to our vendors in accordance with data privacy laws.

For a list of our affiliates by country of incorporation, please click here.

**Retention of your data**  
We will retain your personal data only for as long as is necessary. If you have an account with us, we will only keep the data while your account is active or for as long as needed to provide services to you and, as further needed for us to comply with our global legal and contractual obligations.

**Your rights**  
You are entitled to know whether we hold personal data about you and, if we do, to have access to that personal data and require it to be corrected if it is inaccurate. We generally do not make decisions by purely automatic means, but if we do, you have the right to object.

Contact Us to exercise any of your rights or [download a copy of Accenture's BCR](https://www.accenture.com/t20170802T012846Z__w__/us-en/_acnmedia/PDF-52/Accenture-Public-Facing-BCR-June-2017.pdf#zoom=50 "Click here to download the full article. Description of Accenture’s Binding Corporate Rules. This opens a new window.") **.**

If your data was originally collected in Europe (the European Economic Area (EEA) and Switzerland) and it is transferred from an Accenture entity within Europe to an Accenture entity outside Europe you have the following additional rights under the BCR:

  * to make complaints to, obtain appropriate redress and, where appropriate, receive compensation from the Accenture entity within Europe that originally obtained and processed your personal data, in respect of any damage suffered by you as a result of a breach of the Privacy Policy by any other Accenture entity to which the personal information may have been transferred under the BCR;

  * to lodge a complaint with a competent data protection authority and/ or to take action through a court to enforce compliance by Accenture with the terms of the Privacy Policy;

  * to obtain a copy of the BCR upon request at the following Contact Us link.

**You have a question or complaint**  
If you can’t find what you’re looking for here, or have a concern about our use of your personal data, please Contact Us.

## WEBSITES

**This site is administered by Accenture LLP on behalf of itself and each Accenture local operating company.**

Your privacy on Accenture’s websites  
What information do we gather?  
How do we use information that we collect from the site?

**Your privacy on Accenture’s websites**  
The primary purpose of Accenture’s website is to be a dynamic resource and business tool to help you learn more about Accenture. We want you to feel secure when visiting our website and are committed to maintaining your privacy when doing so.

**What information do we gather?**  
Accenture collects information at its websites in two ways: (1) directly (for example, when you provide information to sign up for a newsletter or register to comment on a forum website); and (2) indirectly (for example, through our website's technology).

We may collect and process the following information:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our website. This includes registering to use the website, subscribing to services, newsletters and alerts, registering for a conference or requesting a white paper or further information. Pages that collect this type of information may provide further information as to why your data is needed and how it will be used. It is completely up to you whether you want to provide it.

  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

  * We may ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.

  * Any postings, comments or other content that you upload or post to an Accenture website.

  * Our website collects information about your computer, including (where available) your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration, to filter traffic, to look up user domains and to report on statistics.

  * Details of your visits to our website, the pages you view and resources you access or download, including but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data. Please see the Cookies section below for more information.

When this information relates to or identifies you, we will treat it as “personal data.”

**How do we use information that we collect from the site?**  
We use personal data to provide you with information you request, process online job applications, and for other purposes which we would describe to you at the point where it is collected or which will be obvious to you. For example:

  * To fulfill your requests for white papers, articles, newsletters or other content.

  * For surveys or research questionnaires.

  * To personalize your experience at our website.

  * To contact you for marketing purposes where you have agreed to this.

We analyze your IP and browser information to determine what is most effective about our website, to help us identify ways to improve it and make it more effective. Please see the Cookies section below for more information.

## COOKIES

We analyze your IP and browser information to determine what is most effective about our website, to help us identify ways to improve it and, eventually, to determine how we can tailor our website to make it a more positive and relevant user experience. Please see our Cookies policy for more details. By using our website you agree that we can place cookies and other similar technologies on your device as explained in our Cookies policy.

## MARKETING

The following describes our use of personal data for marketing purposes:

Sources of marketing data  
Targeted E-mail  
Customer Relationship Management(CRM) Databases  
Use of Accenture Websites  
Combining and Analyzing Personal Data

**Sources of Marketing Data**.   
The bulk of the personal data we collect and use for marketing purposes relates to individual employees of our clients and other companies with which we have an existing business relationship. We may also obtain contact information from public sources, including content made public at social media websites, to make an initial contact with a relevant individual at a client or other company.

**Targeted E-mail**.   
We send commercial e-mail to individuals at our client or other companies with whom we want to develop or maintain a business relationship in accordance with applicable marketing laws. Our targeted e-mail messages typically include web beacons, cookies, and similar technologies that allow us to know whether you open, read, or delete the message, and links you may click. When you click a link in a marketing e-mail you receive from Accenture, we will also use a cookie to log what pages you view and what content you download from our websites, even if you are not registered at or signed into our site.

Targeted e-mails from Accenture may include additional data privacy information, as required by applicable laws.

**Customer Relationship Management (CRM) Databases**.   
Like all large companies, Accenture uses customer relationship management (CRM) database technology to manage and track our marketing efforts. Our CRM databases include personal data belonging to individuals at our client and other companies with whom we already have a business relationship or want to develop one. The personal data used for these purposes includes relevant business information, such as: contact data, publicly available information (e.g. board membership, published articles, press releases, your public posts on social media sites if relevant for business purpose), your responses to targeted e-mail (including web activity following links from our e-mails), website activity of registered users of our website, and other business information included by Accenture professionals based on their personal interactions with you. If you wish to be excluded from our CRM databases, please use the Contact Us form.

**Combining and Analyzing Personal Data**.  
As described above, we may combine data from publicly available sources, and from our different e-mail, website, and personal interactions with you (this includes information collected across our different websites such as our careers and corporate sites and information collected when you sign-up or log on to our sites or connect to our sites using your social media credentials (such as LinkedIn and Xing). We combine this data to better assess your experience with Accenture and to perform the other activities described throughout our privacy policy.

**Your Rights**  
You can exercise your right to prevent marketing communications to you by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your personal data, or by utilizing opt-out mechanisms in e-mails we send to you. You can also exercise the right to discontinue marketing communications to you, or to have your personal data removed from our customer relationship management (CRM) databases at any time by using our Contact Us form. In such cases, we will retain minimum personal data to note that you opted out in order to avoid contacting you again.

## RECRUITING

If you use Accenture’s online career resources, we collect personal data that you submit to the website and use it for recruiting-related purposes. We may also use Cookies and other tracking technology and the same technologies we use for Marketing (including Customer Relationship Management (CRM) Databases, Targeted E-mail & Combining and Analyzing Personal Data) to provide individuals with a personalized online experience, to send relevant information about careers and opportunities at Accenture, and to analyze the effectiveness of our recruitment efforts and resources. More information about how your data will be used by Accenture during the recruitment process will be provided as part of the recruitment process.
